新线电影公司
嘿，给我一瓶
Hey, pass the bottle over.
- 我正在忙好吗?  - 是阿,我们都知道,大卫
- A little busy back here. Okay?  - Yeah, we can see that, David.
是的,你一点都不忙.
Yeah, you can get un-busy.
哦，别这样马西雅。我们翘掉毕业典礼到这地方，你知道我的意思
Oh, come on, Marce. I mean, you know,  we skipped graduation for this.
你还没从处男毕业，大卫.布罗迪
You are not graduating  down there, David Brody.
嘿，你最好不要拍我们。
Hey, you better not be filming us.
没有，我在检查简讯而已
No, just checking messages.
Oh, oh, your Trojan's in my head
那是什么?
What was that?
- 你有看到吗?  - 什么?
- Do you see that?  - What?
你们有看到吗?
Man. You guys seeing this?
- 哇 嘿 比利  - 哇 嘿~ 嘿~ 嘿~
- Whoa. Hey, Billy.  - Whoa. Ho-ho-ho.
等等
Hang on.
- 我们该走了.  - 等一下，我得把这拍下来
- We should go.  - I gotta get this. Hang on.
- 可以走了吗?  - 快走吧。我们快走
- Can we go?  - Come on, let's go.
- 好的 等一下  - 进来!
- Yeah. Hold on.  - Get in!
知道了!给我一分钟
I will! Just give me one minute!
- 快进来!  - 看见了吗?
- Come on!  - Are you seeing this?
- 哇!  - 比利 快走吧!
- Whoa!  - Billy, get in!
天啊! 是龙卷风!
Oh, shit! Tornado!
天啊!
Oh, my God!
快跑 快点离开
Get us out of here. Go!
不 惧 风 暴
龙卷风昨夜袭击了俄克拉荷马州北部地区...
The tornado that struck  Oklahoma last night...
四名高中生在袭击中丧生...
took the lives of four  high school students...
他们的汽车被卷到几百英里外的高空中
when it picked up their car  and tossed it into the air.
龙卷风虽然在中西部地区很常见...
Tornadoes in this region of the Midwest  are common, but it only took a glance...
但是我们看到此次明显非同小可
to know this was different.
它并不是一条细长的风柱而更像一头在夜空中嘶吼的巨兽
Not so much a twisting  column but a behemoth.
太好了 我们又没有赶上
Great. We missed another one.
嘿 大家不会不知道拍纪录片的目的...
Hey, you guys know the  goal of a documentary...
是要记录点什么吧?
is to actually document  something, right?
收到
Copy that.
我们得找到龙卷风
We need a tornado.
没错 得找到龙卷风  我们上次拍是什么时候 卢卡斯?
That's it. We need a tornado. Yeah.  When was the last time we shot one, Lucas?
一年前为气象频道拍的4级龙卷风
That EF4 that we shot a year ago.
是啊 一年了 365天 一无所获
Right. A year ago.  So we're 0 for 365.
这工作快干不下去了  雅各布 你是打棒球吗?
Let's figure that average. Hey,  Jacob, you play baseball. Right?
- 打曲棍球  - 是吗？ 我玩长曲棍球
- Hockey, actually.  - Yeah? I played lacrosse.
- 真的假的  - 真是搞笑 简直就像家庭旅游
- Really? No way.  - This is fun. It's like a family road trip.
- 我说错什么了?  - 是的，雅各布
- Did I miss something?  - Yeah, Jacob.
你不是说错了  而是错过了
You missed everything.
不 没有错过. 我们花了200小时欣赏日落...
No. Except we do have 200  hours of cloud sunsets...
我们还从爱达荷州一路飙车到德克萨斯州
and us going to every drive-through  from Idaho to Texas.
这家庭纪录片简直堪称史上最昂贵的
Which makes this the most  expensive home movie ever.
得先说清楚了
Just to be clear...
找不到龙卷风我们的钱也不会少吧?
we're gonna get paid whether  we see a tornado or not, right?
对吧?
Right?
我们现在去哪，老大?
Where do you wanna go, boss?
我也不知道 达里尔.  我的工作就是负责拍它们...
I have no idea, Daryl.  My job is to shoot them...
...可不负责找它们
...not find them.
- 他心情不好啊
- He's upset.  - What else is new?
接连着抱怨了三个月，我都已经习惯了
Three months of that  broken record. I'm over it.
真庆幸我俩没在他的Titus里窝着
Just be thankful we're in here  and not in the Titus.
- 在那儿肯定惨了  - 没关对讲机 天才们
- Must be brutal in there.  - You left the radio on, genius.
糟糕
Shit.
这下他的心情应该更不好了
That probably didn't help his mood.
他的情绪是小事 龙卷风才是大事
Screw his mood.  We've got other problems.
我们真的没法预测昨天晚上的龙卷风会刮到哪去
There's no way we could have known  that tornado was gonna hit.
国家气象局发布了龙卷风警报...
The National Weather Service  has issued a tornado watch...
德州、俄克拉荷马州、堪萨斯州、阿肯色州、密苏里州境内
throughout Texas, Oklahoma,  Kansas, Arkansas and Missouri.
彼得，国家气象局刚刚针对五个州发布了龙卷风警报
Pete. National Weather posted a  tornado watch across five states.
增长很快 移动速度惊人
Front's growing and moving fast.
我想距离我们以北200英里
I think this thing's gonna hit  about 200 miles north of here.
那我们也得加快了
Then we better haul ass.
如果我们跟它撞个正着 你这一天就不好过了
If you're in the path of this storm,  you could be in for a very long day.
嘿!今天是6月16日...
Hey. So today is June 16th...
这是我给未来自己的时光胶囊
and this is my time capsule  message to the future me.
恩... 记录下来之后将封存25年...
Um... This is gonna be recorded  and stored for 25 years...
当你 41岁的唐尼.福勒看到这个...
when you, the 41-year-old  Donnie Fuller, will...
该怎么说呢 就会回想起这时的生活
I don't know, see how  life's panned out, I guess.
嗯...
Uh...
那个时候爸爸65岁
By now Dad is 65.
那妈妈就会是...
So Mom would have been...
妈妈会是63岁了
Mom would have been 63.
嗯...
Um...
还有什么? 你现在是西威尔顿高级中学高中生
What else? You're a junior  at Silverton High School.
你是摄影俱乐部的老大 听起来很棒嘛!
You're head of the Video Club,  which is awesome.
应该...
And...
差不多就这样
And that's pretty much it.
看 这就是唐尼之家...
So this is Casa de Donnie...
你在这里的大部分时间...
Where you spend most your time...
那是盯着学校纪念册里 凯特琳.强森的照片发呆.
staring at the photo of Kaitlyn  Johnston and doing nothing.
- 这是特雷 讨人嫌的弟弟  - 我们彼此彼此
- This is Trey, your annoying brother.  - Respect to you too.
等你看见这个的时候 特雷肯定正在监狱呆着呢
By the time you see this,  Trey's gonna be in the state pen.
嘿.别闹了，那时我肯定是在麦迪逊广场花园  对着十万的粉丝狂飙吉他
Heh. No way. I will be playing lead guitar  to 100,000 fans in Madison Square Garden.
但是你...肯定还会在这老地方 对着她的照片呻吟
But you will be stuck right here,  moaning over her.
这是爸爸。他是西威尔顿中学的副校长...
This is Dad. He's the vice principal  at Silverton High School...
这对我来说可不是什么好事
which is not the greatest for me.
- 嗯, 老爸  - 嗯?
- Uh, Dad?  - Hmm?
嘿!别拍了 我正在吃早餐
Hey, come on.  I'm having breakfast here.
- 特雷 5分钟后出发 准备好了吗?  - 别着急
- Trey, I am leaving in five, ready or not.  - Relax!
爸，要对未来说点什么吗?
Wanna say something to  the future you, Dad?
不， 唐尼 看不出来我今天很忙吗?
Not now, Donnie, okay?  Busy day. Can't you see that?
爸爸，之前你...
Dad, you're the one...
不是要我先拍摄这些时光胶囊的吗?
that wanted these video-time-capsule  pieces in the first place.
这鬼天气会把毕业典礼给搞砸了
This weather's gonna kill  the graduation ceremony.
我们应该延期举行
We should postpone it.
好了，这是时光胶囊纪录的第二版
Okay. This is time-capsule  interview, version number two.
我是什么样的人?  这是一个很难回答的问题
What kind of man am I?  That's a hard question to answer.
我是说 完美这个词 简直就是为我而创造的
I mean, how do you  describe perfection?
我以为你早拍摄完了
I thought you did your  interview already.
没错 昨天下午就拍完了
I did. Yesterday.
但是我突然想起来在晨光中我会显得更帅
But then I remembered I look  way better in the morning light.
加油呀 老爸
Lift with your legs, Dad.
孩子们 过来帮帮我
Come on, guys, I could use some help.
老爸 我爱莫能助 我的背上有踢球时留下的旧伤
Ah, man, I can't. That old  soccer-injury thing with my back.
- 是吗? 这些都录进去了?  - 是的
- Yeah? You get all that?  - I did.
很好 快上车
Good. Get in.
抢位置!
Shotgun!
- 唐尼 一起走  - 我骑脚踏车去
- Donnie, let's go.  - I'm taking my bike.
老哥 你想坐前座让给你好了
Dude. Chill. If you  want shotgun, just take it.
嘿, 我很抱歉，但龙卷风和毕业典礼让我忙得焦头烂额
Hey, I'm sorry. With the storm and  graduation today, I got a lot on my plate.
- 我知道 你总是忙 我早习惯了  - 这话什么意思?
- I know. It's always something. I'm used to it.  - What does that mean?
你别总是要么忽视我 要么盯着我不放
It means you're either  ignoring me or on my case.
- 不是这样的  - 不是说我房间乱 就是说我成绩差
- That's not true.  - If it's not my room, it's my grades.
努力去做什么傻呼呼的时光胶囊 你又不当一回事
Or it's this time capsule, which I'm  working my ass off to get done.
这样有什么意义? 你永远都不会满意
No. What's the point?  Nothing's ever good enough for you.
等等，我们好好谈一谈
Stop for second. Let's talk.
不行 我很忙。看不出来吗? 爸爸
No. Busy day, Dad.  Can't you see that?
好吧, 老爸 老爸
All right, Dad. Dad.
别想太多 凭你的直觉马上说出来
Right at this moment... Don't even think  about it before you answer. Just blurt it out.
...哪个是你最喜欢的儿子?
...who is your favorite son?
你给我上车
Get in the car.
来了
Well.
我知道昨晚我们错过了，没能及时赶到现场
I know we missed it last night.  We couldn't get there in time.
是啊 我知道
Yeah. I know. I know.
如果你撤资 我就完蛋了
Well, if you pull my funding,  that's it for me.
而且这次追的是个大家伙.
And we're onto a big one.
我不知道有多大，史帝夫 那是龙卷风
I don't know how big. It's a tornado.
它们不会事先打电话告诉我有多大
They don't call to tell me  how big they're gonna be.
总之风暴前缘很大 正穿过那个地区
There's a massive storm front  moving through the area.
我们一定会找到它的
We're gonna get it.  We just don't have it yet.
呃，让她来可是你的主意?
Uh, well, she was your idea.
我要的是大卫 你没忘吧?
I wanted David Sinclair, remember?
就算没有艾莉森和她的数据，我也快成功了
Yeah. Well, I was getting a lot  closer without Allison and her data.
这可是个玩直觉的游戏
It's an instinct game.
她只懂数据
And she ain't got it.
嘿，雅各布 能帮个忙?
Hey, Jacob. A little help?
- 不行啊 如果我停下来 彼得会炒了我的
- I can't. If I stop filming, Pete's gonna fire me.  - Dude.
你可别白受他的气
Don't you dare let him bully you.
你说的容易，又不是你坐在他旁边
Easy for you to say. You're not  the one sitting next to him.
这次有意思吗?
You having fun yet?
是的 老兄，这比坎昆那次有意思多了
Oh, yeah, dude. This is so  much better than Cancun.
跟你说吧 去年我们离它就一百码的距离
I'm telling you, last year  we got within 100 yards.
那景象真是叹为观止 相信我
It's like nothing you've  seen before. Trust me.
好吧 你看，更大规模的正如预计的在向河岸移动
Okay, so larger system is moving  toward Riverside as predicted.
我觉得我们应该去这边
I think we should go here.
风速和降水指数对形成龙卷风来说是不错的数值
The wind and precipitation readings in  the trailing cell look better for a funnel.
之前莫里斯敦和奥斯古德地区的龙卷风 你也这样说
Exactly what you said about  Morristown and Osgood.
- 不，这次不一样  - 有什么不一样?
This one's different. It's not following  the pattern. It's growing faster.
这不是普通的情况 这次增长非常快
It's growing faster.
而且 夏威夷这边所有的风暴迷都去了河岸边
Every storm chaser this side of  Hawaii is going to Riverside.
我想说的是 我觉得我们也该去那边
Which, by the way, is where  I think we should go.
你想我们去哪? 西威尔顿?
But you want us to  go where? Silverton?
我知道你是把这个当成和直觉有关的东西  而不是和数据有关的东西
If you would like, consider this an  instinct thing instead of a data thing.
如果你听到了我说的   那你一定也听到了史帝夫想撤资
If you heard that, then you also  heard that Steve cut us off.
- 现在我在用自己的钱  - 我是听到了
- And it's on my dime now.  - I heard that.
你也跟我们在路上跑了三个月
This is months on the road.  And guess what.
结果是我们拍到的东西Youtube上都有，我讨厌现在的情况
We got nothing you can't get on YouTube.  Worst season I've ever had.
你觉得这是个直觉游戏，我觉得这是个数据游戏
You think this is instinct.  I think it's data.
而实际上 这两种都不是，这其实是个运气游戏
The fact is, it's neither  without a big fat dose of luck.
老天给的运气我可控制不了，好吗?
And there is nothing I  can do about that. Okay?
我们别再争执了
So back off of me.
我只想让你和你的数据  给我找到一个该死的龙卷风
I just want you and your data  to find me a goddamn tornado.
西威尔顿就是我们的机会
Then Silverton's our best chance.
你怎么想的?
What do you think?
她是这方面的权威
She's the one with all the degrees.
我赌她赢
My money's on her.
那就去西威尔顿
Silverton it is.
最好这次你是对的
You better be right about this.
- 这是你最后的机会  - 好吧
- It's your last chance.  - Wow.
等等 等等 好了
Yeah, okay. Hang on. Okay. It's okay.
好了 我们开始录了吗?
All right. We recording?
- 感觉很不错?  - 准备好了吗?
- We're good?  - You ready?
- 超级好 老兄  - 好的 开始吧!
- Hell, yeah, man!  - Yeah! Get fired up!
- 我准备好了
- I'm ready!  - You ready for this shit?
或许我们应该找几个小妞来看这个特技 对吧?
Maybe we should get some  girls to watch this stunt, huh?
这就是我说的猛男啦啦队!  该大显身手了，宝贝
That's what I'm talking about. Get fired up!  Let's go for real! It's go time!
- 来吧 来吧  - 安全第一
- Let's go, let's go!  - Safety first.
开始吧，先试一次好吗? 快让开 混蛋
Okay, just do a test run first,  all right? Move, jackass!
- 都给我闪开 我要冲过去了  - 来吧 你行的 兄弟
- Get out of the way. Here we go.  - Come on. Yeah. You got it, buddy.
- 加油 兄弟  - 加油 唐克 来吧 兄弟
- Come on, buddy!  - Come on, Donk! Let's go, boy!
他在测试速度呢
He's gonna check the  speed on this one.
兄弟 来吧 上啊
Yeah! Do it, bro!
- 开起来  - 来个试跳
- Let's go!  - Test drive!
来个试跳 来呀
Let's go for the test drive!
你去哪，唐克!
There you go, Donkie!
你看起来相当不错，有什么感想?
Well, that looked pretty good to me.  What do you think?
嗯...
Eh.
你说什么? 你还想不想泡妞 老兄
What? You wanna nail  some tail or what, dog?
- 我时时刻刻都准备泡妞 宝贝  - 这才像样
- I'm always up for nailing tail!  - That's what I'm talking about.
这影片一但上网，会传疯的
Once this hits the Internet,  you'll be beating them off with a stick.
- 四星? 五星? 各钟类型?  - 至少是五星 六星的
- Fours? Fives? All kinds?  - I'm talking fives, sixes.
一定有五星 加油!
Fives, for sure. Come on!
- 好的  - 相信我，哥们!
- Bam!  - Trust me, buddy!
好的 来吧
Yeah! All right! Hang on.
- 等等 里奇在干嘛?  - 你喝醉了吗?
- Richie! Record this, son.  - Are you drunk?
- Yeah.
- I'm just getting started.  - 我要开始了
唐克 等一下!我们把这水池点燃
Hang on! Wait! We're gonna  light the pool on fire.
- 点燃它 里奇  - 对 点然它 快点
- Light that thing, Richie!  - Yeah! Light it up!
火烧屁股
Light that puppy up.
- 哇!  - 我的天啊!
- Whoa!  - Oh, my God!
死亡之火水池!
The Flaming Pool of Death!
你准备好了吗?
You ready to go?
开始吧
Let's do this!
开始!
Action!
来吧 唐克 你行的
That's right! Come on, Donk!  You got this!
我死定了!
Oopsie daisy!
- 太棒了 哈哈哈  - 哈哈哈.
- That was awesome. Ha-ha-ha.  - Ha-ha-ha.
- 哈哈哈.  - 真是太棒了，唐克
- Ha-ha-ha.  - That was awesome, Donk.
- 轻松搞定一百万点击率!  - 喔! 一百万?
- A million hits, easy!  - Oh! A million?
- 说不定更多!  - 没错老兄 我们就快成名啦
- Maybe more!  - Hell, yeah, dude! We're gonna be famous!
- 混蛋 我的游泳池!  - 唐克, 你妈来了 你妈来了
- Shit, my pool!  - Dude, your mom. Your mom.
你们在这里搞什么鬼?
What the hell are  you two idiots doing?
- 妈 我以为你去上班了  - 所以你们就胡作非为 是吗?
- I thought you were at work!  - That makes any difference?
快看!
Look!
- 那是Titus追风车，我在电视上看过 快来!  - ByeBye，老妈
- That's the Titus! I've seen it on TV! Come on!  - Bye, Ma!
我给大家介绍一下这个终极追风车Titus
Let's take a tour of the ultimate  storm-chasing vehicle, the Titus.
它配备了24小时监测摄影镜头  不管从哪个角度都可纪录影像
She's equipped with 24 surveillance cameras,  so we have eyes from every angle.
特种防弹玻璃窗
Bulletproof Lexan windows.
360度减震摄影镜头
A gyroscopic stabilized camera.
5吨级绞盘
A five-ton winch.
4毫米脱氧钢装甲外壳
Four-millimeter solid steel armor.
后面这里，我们还配有一个迷你气象中心...
Now, back here, we have a mini  weather center, complete with...
一个风速计 湿度侦测器和电位计
an anemometer, humidity  sensor and potentiometer.
而它还有一个最特殊的地方 就是这个抓锚
But the thing that makes her really  special are these grappling claws.
啊
Ah.
它可以在风速每小时170英里的状况巍然耸立
They can stabilize us in winds  up to 170 miles an hour.
要是我们用到抓锚就是遇上末日飓风了
We're not going anywhere  with those suckers dug in.
闪开！
Clear!
这宝贝是我一生的心血
This is the culmination  of my life's work.
那塔台呢 彼得?
What about the turret, Pete?
是的 塔台在这里
Right. The turret is up here.
塔台给我们360度室外的观测角度
Which gives us a 360-degree  view of outside.
还配备了一台数位摄影机  在我们找到这些龙卷风的时候...
It's fitted with a digital cinema camera that  will, when we find one of these bad boys...
能够让我们成为世纪英雄
give us the shot of the century.
这上帝之眼能帮我们见证一切
A sight nobody but God has witnessed:
龙卷风之眼！
the eye of the tornado.
这是“切”的意思 雅各布，停止吧
That means "cut," Jacob. Cut it.
再拍点补充资料
Let's get some B roll.
拍一点抓锚 汽车背部的零件 控制面板
Get shots of the claws, the instruments  on the back, panel stuff.
- 拍点有用的东西给我，好吗?  - 好的 知道了
- Just give me stuff I can use. Okay?  - Got it.
这里的风暴不断膨胀扩大
My storm's expanding.
意味着到这里的时候会变得巨大无比
That means it's going to be really  big by the time it gets here.
嗨.
Hey.
我的宝贝好吗?
How's my bug?
听我说...
Well, listen, um...
妈妈说过这个星期赶回去...
I know I was gonna try and  make it home this weekend...
但是我们遇到一场很大的风暴  妈妈必须留下来工作
but we got a real big storm coming,  and Mama's gotta work.
不是 不是 我希望你告诉外公外婆...
No. No. I'm gonna need you to tell  Grandma and Grandpa that we're...
我知道
I know.
我知道 乖孩子 对不起
I know, sweet girl. I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
格蕾丝...
Gracie...
Grace...
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.
在拍我吗?
Did you get all that?
我们不能延期 盖瑞 那地方装不下所有的学生
We can't postpone this, Gary. There's  not enough room inside for everyone.
- 现在天气就挺不错的，不用那么担心  - 好吧 你来决定
- The weather's gonna be fine.  - It's your call.
那是爸爸正在被沃克校长训斥
There's Dad taking shit  from Principal Walker.
我会照办的
I Will do that.
最后部分弄好了吗?
Did you get the last  of the interviews?
没有 还差的远呢
I still got a few to do.
但是我拍到了贝尔老师的事业线，想看吗?
But what I did get was a nice shot  of Miss Bell's cleavage. Wanna see?
特雷
Trey.
怎么了?可没几个化学老师有事业线
What? You don't get many  teachers with a rack like that.
你别再闹了行吗，毕业典礼后得马上开始剪辑
Cut it out. We need to start  editing right after graduation.
爸爸希望下周末影片就可以上传
Dad wants the clips online  by the end of next week.
做一个影片时光胶囊到底有什么意义?
What's the point of doing  a video time capsule?
影片根本不会在网站上保留25年的
Video won't even exist in 25 years.
行了 赶紧把它做完行吗?
What? Let's just get  it finished. Okay?
好吧
Fine.
你看天气预报了吗?可能会有大风暴来袭
Did you see the weather report?  Supposed to be a big storm coming.
也许他们会取消整个...
Maybe they'll cancel the whole...
哇.你喜欢的女孩
Whoa. There's your girl.
如果我今天之前没有拿到资料，你就没法参加实习
If I don't get it by the end of the day,  you'll not get the internship.
就这么简单
It's as simple as that.
喔 可怜的女孩，老兄 你的机会来了
Oh, dude. Now's your  chance, man. Vulnerable girl.
去和她讲几句话安慰一下
Comforting guy. Right? Just go  talk to her and see if she's okay.
- 我们还有工作要做  - 胆小鬼，快去
- We have work to do.  - Chickenshit. Come on.
我得把影片弄完，还有爸爸那部分够烦的了
I need to get the last of the interviews,  and Dad's, like, on my case about it.
别管老爸了，为了你自己去做点什么事吧
Screw Dad. Go do something  for yourself for once.
老哥，我拜托你就只是去跟他说说话
Bro, I am literally begging you.  Just go talk to her.
可以吗?
All right?
好吧
All right.
可以吗?
Yeah?
- 够了  - 嘿
- Stop.  - Heh.
玩得开心
Have fun.
他真的这样做了  我要去拍下这场好戏
He's really doing it.  I gotta film this train wreck.
他马上要就定位了
And he's pulling into the station.
嗨, 凯特琳?
Hey, Kaitlyn?
嗨
Hey.
我是唐尼
It's Donnie.
我知道
Yeah. I know.
第一招成功
Strike one.
你还好吗? 我在外面看见你跟布兰斯基小姐
Are you okay? I saw you  outside with Miss Blasky.
还好，呃...
Right. Uh...
我申请了暑假实习班必须在这周末前交出
I had this application for an apprenticeship,  and it had to be submitted by the weekend.
但布兰斯基小姐检查后却告诉我这影片完全损坏了
And Miss Blasky checked it for me,  and it's just completely corrupted.
我不知道发生了什么事
I don't know what happened to it.
昨天还是好好的
It was fine yesterday.
好的 好的，是关于什么的影片?
Yeah. Yeah, that's toast.  What was it about?
加纳街上的废弃工厂
The abandoned factory on Garner.
- 天呐 那个造纸厂吗?  - 对啊
- Oh, the paper mill?  - Yeah.
对
Yeah.
那个工厂关闭的时候州政府没有付钱做清扫
When they shut it down, the state  never paid for an official cleanup.
所以那些化学药剂和危险材料堆积的到处都是...
So there's all these chemicals and  hazardous materials sitting there...
甚至可能污染了城市的供水系统
contaminating the soil and probably  running off into the water.
- 这就是影片的主题  - 假装对这有兴趣
- That's what the film's about.  - Pretend to be interested.
申请书如果没有这部分 就没意义了
Anyway, the submission doesn't  make any sense at all without it.
- 我算彻底完蛋了  - 加油 老哥 提供点意见
- So I'm screwed.  - Come on, man. Take a swing.
- 你这么关心环保的事情?  - 上啊 老哥 约她出去
- You're into all this environmental stuff, huh?  - Come on, man. Just ask her out.
因为要保护地球 对吧?
Gotta take care of the planet, right?
要不然地球就会对我们反扑，对吧?
Or else the planet will take  care of us, right? Heh.
真是尴尬
That was awkward.
没错，反正我是真的关心 而且愿意尝试去做
Heh. Yeah. Well, some of us care,  or at least are trying to.
真不好意思
No. I'm sorry.
我可以帮你解决问题，我有很多摄影机和剪辑软件...
I can help. I have all these cameras  and this editing software and...
- 真的吗?  - 对
- Really?  - Yeah.
这不是什么难事 我们可以重新拍
Well, this will be easy.  We can reshoot this.
- 今天必须完成  - 今天?!
- It'd have to be today.  - Today?
哦，你在拍毕业影片  没关系 我自己可以的
Oh, you're filming the graduation.  No, it's fine.
没关系 我弟弟特雷，他也很擅长拍毕业影片
No. No. My brother, Trey,  he's good with all this stuff too.
- 可以让他帮我做  - 不行
- He can get that.  - No way.
- 他完全可以去搞定那个影片  - 真的吗?
- Like, he can get that footage.  - Really?
- 真的 真的 没问题  - 你确定?
- It's not a problem.  - Sure?
- 当然了 确定  - 别想 当然有问题
- Yes, it's a problem.  - I'm sure. Yeah.
太感谢你了
Thank you so much.
不，你不知道这对我有多重要，我欠你一个大人情
No. You have no idea what this means  for me. I owe you so big for this.
别这样说，其实我和地球交情很深...
No. Well, you know, me and  the planet go way back, so...
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 我稍后就找你  - 没问题
- I'll see you later.  - Cool.
- 谢谢  - 不客气
- Thank you.  - Okay, no.
这小子真没勇气
This is so not cool.
你是在开玩笑吗?
You are kidding me.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
你真打算逃掉毕业典礼吗??
You're gonna skip the ceremony?
是啊 没错
Yeah. Yeah.
不是你说让我主动争取吗，我现在争取到了
You said do something for yourself,  so I'm doing something for myself.
真棒 所以你要丢下我一个人?
Yeah. And leaving me  to do all the filming?
你能搞定的 对吧?
You can handle it. Right?
你应该没问题吧?
You can handle it, right?
- 那倒是  - 好吧
- Yes.  - Heh.
当然了 勇往直前吧 老哥
Yeah. Yeah. Totally. Hey.  You go for it, bro.
记得顺便拍点不雅的影片寄Email给我
But get some skin on camera.  E-mail it to me.
- 把我们的影片做完好吗?  - 好的  我这就去做
- Just get the interviews, all right?  - All right, all right, I'm going.
谢了
Okay.
托德 开始拍了
Yo, Todd. We're rolling.
你好吗?未来你过的怎么样 哥们?
Yo, what's up, me?  How's life in the future, bro?
我刚听说你最近正在打NBA 而且超级有钱...
So I just know by now you are playing  for the NBA, you're super loaded...
你老婆还是个超级辣的啦啦队队长
and you got a super-smoking-hot  cheerleader wife.
那你现在干嘛看这玩意呢?
So why the hell are you  watching this right now?
为何还不去你的高级别墅和老婆好好享受人生，对吧?
Why don't you get up to your  penthouse and bang her good, right?
这就是你给自己的时光胶囊 托德?
That's your time-capsule  message, Todd?
有问题吗?
Why not?
时光胶囊!?
A message?
我是用不上了 这些家伙也用不上了  给我的孩子和孙子 很简单
Too late for me. Too late for these guys.  But my kids? Grandkids? Simple.
好好读书 拿个高学历
Study. Get good grades.
要不然就会跟我们这些家伙一样天天当苦工，抱歉
Or else you're gonna hang around this group  of losers shoveling shit all day. Sorry.
嫁个有钱人...嫁个有钱人...
Please marry a rich guy.  Please marry a rich guy.
呃, 已经开始拍了
Uh, we're rolling.
你想跟25年后的自己说些什么?
So, what would you like to  say to yourself in 25 years?
刚刚已经说了
That was it.
25年之后?! 我想那个时候整个世界恐怕都被炸飞了
Twenty-five years' time? Ha! My guess is  we'd have blown up the world by that time.
好吧
All right.
面对现实 高中真的很烂
High school sucked.
希望一切都没白费，你成为布朗大学的博士
Hopefully, it was all worth it.  You've got your Ph.D. from Brown.
你正在做的研究可以帮助...
You're doing research and  using your skills to help...
别再妄想了! 哈!
Douche-rocket! Ha!
抱歉了 老兄
Sorry, man.
- 无线电测试  - 是的
- Radio check.  - Yes, sir.
收到
Copy that.
摄影机测试良好
Camera's good.
嘿，伙计们 你认为我们今天会看到龙卷风吗?
Hey, guys. So you think we'll get  to see a tornado today or what?
这可不好说
You never know.
雅各布，你有看到全部的相机电池吗?  我只看到四个
Jacob, did you bring all the  camera batteries? I only saw four.
我...呃... 出门时放在旅馆充电
I, uh, left them back  at the hotel on charge.
今天不能没有电力，马上得回去拿
Today is not a good day to run out  of power. We gotta go get them.
开始行动吧  暴风一小时内就到了，它可不等人
Let's get moving. This system's  supposed to hit within the hour.
说不定更快
If that.
拜托 老兄 照顾好自己 我都没面子了
Come on, dude, get your shit together,  man. You're making me look bad.
麦克风测试 1 2 3
Mike check. One, two, three.
- 唐尼在哪里?  - 麦克风测试
- Where's Donnie?  - Mike check.
- 测试良好  - 我不知道，大概在附近吧
- Yeah, it's good.  - I don't know. Around.
- 他知道毕业典礼什么时候开始吗?  - 是的，他知道
- He knows what time we're starting?  - Yeah, sure.
不管怎样，我可以操作摄影机
Anyway, I can run the cameras.
全部三台?
All three?
嗯，是的，爸爸。这就是为什么发明了三脚架。
Well, yes, Dad. That's why  they invented tripods.
特雷，这是很重要的事情。
Trey, this is important.
我不能胜任吗?
And I can't do it, right?
我没有这样说
I didn't say that.
你就是这意思
You kind of did.
嗨，妈妈。怎么样格蕾丝？  她还在生气呢？
Hey, Mom. How's Gracie?  She still mad?
她才5岁  她没事的
She's 5 years old. She'll be fine.
我知道，但我已经离开三个月了  离开她太久了
I know, but I've been gone for months.  That's too long to be away from her.
我一直在想 是不是不该来这里
I keep thinking it was  a mistake coming here.
艾莉森，我们很好
MRS. McGEE: Allison, we're fine.
你的工作是很重要的
This is your job.  What you're doing is important.
我脑袋里总是那几个死了的小孩
I can't stop thinking about  those kids that died.
什么小孩?
What kids?
没什么，亲爱的。奶奶和妈妈在随便聊聊，听着
Nothing, sweetie. Grandma and  Mama were just talking. But listen.
之前的事我很抱歉，我不想让你生气
I am sorry about our call earlier, okay?  I don't want you mad at me.
你什么时候回家
When are you coming home?
就快了。坏天气就快结束了
Real soon. The season's almost over.
为什么不能现在回来?
Why can't you just come now?
我也希望如此  我真的很想念你
I wish I could.  I really do. I miss you.
艾莉森
Allison!
听着，我得走了，我每隔几个小时再联络，好吗?
Listen, I gotta go. But I'm gonna  check in every couple hours, okay?
答应我，你很快就会回家？
Promise me you'll be home soon?
我保证
I promise.
艾莉森
Allison!
我得走了。我爱你，宝贝
I gotta go. I love you, bug.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我来了,老大!
I'm coming, boss!
现在我们已经证实，龙卷风袭击河岸.
We have now confirmed that a  tornado has hit Riverside.
整个城镇处于严重的雷暴与警戒范围
All of Shaw County remains under  a severe thunderstorm warning.
查克,你在雷达上看见什么?
Chuck, what do you see on radar?
好的，史帝夫 我们现在看到它移动非常快速...
What we're watching  now is this very rapid...
- 数据，是吧？  - Shit！
- Data, huh?  - Shit.
也许我们到最后尾巴也没抓住
Maybe we'll catch the tail end of it.
- 西威尔顿发生了什么事?  - 给我一分钟
- What's going on in Silverton?  - Give me a minute.
呃, 龙卷风正在消散 有分散的雷暴雨现象
Um, it's dissipating. There's some scattered  thunderstorms and that's about it.
雷暴雨? 雷暴雨
Thunderstorms? Thunderstorms.
把所有的东西放到车上  我们要走了
Put everything in the van.  We're moving now.
我们要去哪?
Where do you wanna go?
嗯...没有你 只有我们  我们现在去河岸地区
You're not going anywhere.  We are going to Riverside.
-彼得 我觉得我们还是...  -我们会遇到下一个的
- How about...?  - We'll catch the next one.
听着 不会再有下一个了
Look. There's not  gonna be a next one.
出发了
Let's go.
这冰雹可真大
Look at the size of them!
- 你刚才不是说在消散吗?  - 是在消散
- I thought you said it was dissipating.  - It was.
- 你去哪?  - 我要去看看多普勒雷达!
- Where you going?  - I'm gonna check the Doppler!
我跟你去, 艾莉森.
Right behind you, Allison.
哇, 等等
Whoa, wait! Wait up!
艾莉森，看见这些了吗? 实在太大了
Oh, you see these, Allison?  These are huge!
看见了
Yeah!
真是该死
Ow! Son of a bitch!
我的天啊!看看这些 比高尔夫球还大
Oh, my God! Look at these, guys!  They're bigger than golf balls!
快点 快点跑
Ah! Come on! Hurry up! Let's go!
- 有什么情况?  - 风力重新聚集了
- What do we got?  - It's regenerating.
然后呢?
And?
西威尔顿
Silverton.
它来了
It's coming.
好极了
Great.
致今年毕业的所有同学们...
To all the students of this  year's graduating class...
他们付出辛苦和努力终于迎来盼望已久的这一天...
who have dedicated themselves to the  hard work necessary to reach this day...
你们已正式步入成人的世界
you are now standing on  the threshold of adult life.
你们现成可以自由选择自己人生道路
You are free to take your own path...
你们选择的道路不尽相同
and that path will be  different for all of you.
但终将造就你们自己的精彩人生
But it's now time to  create your own lives.
命运掌握在你们自己手里
To create your own destiny.
你快看这个地方
I mean, look at this place.
他们真应该好好整理 彻底消毒
They should tear it down.  Decontaminate it.
种些树或是建一座花园之类的
Plant some trees or a  garden or something.
他们应该在这造一个滑板公园
They should totally  build a skate park here.
哦不，花园  我觉得花园很好
No, a garden. Definitely a garden.
Yeah.  Yeah.
那你是不是想把三脚架放在那边?
So you wanna just put the  tripod down over there?
- 哇  - 嘿.
- Wow.  - Hmm.
- 小心脚下  - 是啊
- Watch your step.  - Yeah.
看上去可以吗?
I look okay?
很好 看起来很漂亮
Yeah. You look beautiful.
我准备一下 就开始拍了...
I wasn't saying...  I was, like, for the...
你什么时候准备好就...
I don't know. Uh, I'm rolling here.
谢谢 唐尼，你太好了
- So whenever you're ready to...  - Thanks, Donnie. You're really sweet.
好吧
Right.
彼得 你在哪?
Pete, where are you?
我马上过去
I'm coming right up.
- 云墙往东移动了  - 哇
- Got wall cloud to the east.  - Whoa.
是啊，但是没有看到漩涡流
Yeah, but no vortex.
- 雅各布 在这边  - 这边出现气体循环了 看到了
- Jacob. I got some circulation over here.  - Over here, got it.
正向那些树移动过去
It's heading towards those trees.
我在橡木街
I'm on Oakwood Road.
如果你现在身处绍尔县，你需要给自己找一个安全的避难所
If you're in Shaw County, you need  to get yourself to a safe place now.
这场风暴将向右移动，几乎直达城镇中心
This thing is going to track right,  almost towards town.
它现在已经来了。你能看到巨大的云墙
There it is now. You can  see the wall cloud.
它慢慢移动到东部
It's lower as it  transitions to the east.
- 靠近南边。在基地的右后方  - 哇 快看看那个.
- Just south. Right behind the base.  - Wow. Look at that.
来吧 宝贝
Come on, baby.
来吧 宝贝 来吧 宝贝
Come on, baby. Come on, baby.
那些白痴在干嘛?
What are those idiots doing?
- 真是太漂亮了  - 哇!
- Aw, this is a beauty!  - Whoo!
真厉害 暴风猎人来啦，宝贝!
Yeah! Twista Hunterz, baby!
开到空地上! 开到空地上!
Get in the field! Get in the field!
看那个烟囱云
Look at that funnel.
我们看到漩涡了。来啊 开始了
We got a vortex. Come on.  Here we go, guys. Here we go.
有碎片
There's debris.
-雅各布 你拍到了吗  -当然
- Jake, you getting this?  - Oh, yeah.
就在那边 在那边
There it is.
这个龙卷风刚刚着地
This tornado just touched down.  We can see it from here.
我们可以看到树被连根拔起  它所到之处所有的东西都被卷入了漩涡
It's ripping up trees.  It's ripping up everything in sight.
要是你在地面必须赶快找一个避难所  找一个安全地点
If you're above ground, you need to get to  a storm shelter or a safe place right now.
名作家约翰.厄普代克说:
I leave you with John Updike's words:
"若想掌握世界就必须学习更多
"You cannot help but learn more as  you take the world into your hands.
永怀虔诚的心...
Take it up reverently...
因世界就是古老的泥土 印满千万人民的指纹"
for it is an old piece of clay,  with millions of thumbprints on it."
好极了
Oh, great.
我想我们应该，呃...
I guess we should, uh...
我想我们应该接近尾声了
I guess we should start  finishing up, then.
哇! 瞧那家伙真大!
Whoo! Look at the  size of that sucker!
瞧它转得多快 老兄!
Look how fast it's spinning, man!
该死 差一点啊!
Shit! Man, that was close!
老兄 我汗毛立起来了
Dude. My arm hairs.
不 老兄 你的头发更严重
No. Dude, it's your "hairs" hairs!
- 它们全在你头上站起来了 老兄!  - 哈哈哈.
- They're standing up on your head, bro!  - Ha-ha-ha.
来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
- 这就是我跟你说过的涡度拉升  - 该我们了 该我们了，快走
- That's the vorticity stretching.  - We're on, we're on. Let's move!
- 一个陆地龙卷风  - 出发了
- I wanna report a tornado on the ground.  - Let's go.
目前还没造成任何破坏 但已接近住宅区
There's no damage yet,  but it's in a semi-residential area.
大概在俄克拉荷马州 西威尔顿以北十五公里的地方
About 15 miles to the north  of Silverton, Oklahoma.
高中生! 全体起立!
Seniors! Stand up!
全体起立!
Stand up!
向你们致敬
We salute you!
欢呼毕业吧! 耶~
All right! Ah.
大家都进去
Go inside, guys.
- 保持冷静 依序往里面走  - 大家都快进去
- Stay calm! Move inside in an orderly fashion!  - Everybody, back inside.
- 转移到大楼里  - 大家快点.
- To the main building.  - Dude, come on.
大家不要慌不要挤
Quickly as you can.
糟糕
Shit!
快进去! 快跑啊 快跑!
Here we go! Quickly! Come on!
快进去! 来吧 这边走
Here we go! Come on, this way.
彼得 告诉我最新进展
Pete, give me an update.
在格兰特街和马尔科姆街附近找到拦截点
I'm gonna find the intercept  near Grant and Malcolm.
- 从东侧靠近它  - 雅克布 调整焦点
- Approach it from the east.  - Jake, you're out of focus. Tighten up.
你必须定位好自己的位置，这家伙移动得非常快
You need to position yourself.  This thing is moving fast.
我需要视野好的空地
I need a clear path.
你的右侧有一块空地可以使用
I got a field coming up on your  right that should have access.
给我点时间计算旋转速度
Give me a second to  calculate rotation speed.
你快点
Make it fast.
- 风速是140  - 方向呢?
- Wind speed is 140.  - Direction?
东南方
Southeast.
- 卢卡斯 好了吗?  - 是的 好了
- Lucas, we good?  - Yeah. We good. We good.
拍到这个了吗? 雅各布
You getting this, Jacob?
哦 那是必须的
Oh, yeah. Sure.
好了 准备拦截
Okay. Ready for intercept.
达里尔 靠边停车
Daryl, pull over.
- 出来吧 你这家伙 快出来  - 看看我吧
- Get out there, dog! Get out there!  - Look at me!
- 我在龙卷风里! 我在龙卷风里!  - 哇!
- I'm in a tornado! I'm in a tornado!  - Whoo!
- 太棒了!  - 我的天啊!
- Yeah!  - Oh, my God!
我们在龙卷风路径上
We're in the path! We're in the path!
好的 放下抓锚 看上去怎么样?
Okay. Anchor down. How we looking?
- 它正朝着你们过去了  - 准备好了 伙计们
- It's heading right for you.  - Get ready, guys.
天啊
Oh, shit.
该死 我的天啊
Oh, shit! Oh, my God!
雅各布 千万别慌 听见了吗?
Jacob! Don't you lose  it on me, you hear?
稳住了 小伙子们
Hold on, boys!
该死 加油啊 加油
Shit! You guys, come on, now!
天啊 这太疯狂了
This is crazy, you guys.  This is nuts.
来吧 来吧
Come on, come on! God!
该死，有东西飞过来了
Shit, that thing is crazy!
坚持住
Hang on!
它来了  快
It's coming right! Go! Go on!
真糟糕
Damn it!
它跑到我们的左侧
It dodged to our left.
惨了
Oh, shit.
它向学校的方向去了
It's headed for the school.
所有人 赶紧走 快进去
Everybody! Okay, go!
就这样 一直走 一直走到大厅
Here we go. Here we go. Keep moving.  All the way down the hall.
一定要让门开着
Keep this door open. Come on.
- 来啊 进去吧 大家都进去吧  - 快点
- Move on in, folks. Move in.  - Come on.
我的天啊
Jesus.
每个人都赶快去暴风雨避难所
Everybody into the  storm shelter area.
- 不要挤在走廊  - 快走吧
- Keep this hallway clear.  - Come on.
- 一定确保没人留下  - 一直走到底
- Make sure nobody's behind us.  - All the way down!
继续走 一直走到底
Go on, all the way in.
特雷 唐尼在哪?
Trey! Where's Donnie?
呃，我真的不知道
Uh, I don't exactly know.
你离窗户远一点
Get away from the window.
龙卷风!
Tornado!
快离开 快跑 快跑
Get going! Run!
快 快走  继续走 一直往大礼堂走 别停下来
Come on! Come on!  Let's go! Go, go, go!
别停
It's okay!
一直往大礼堂走 别停下 快一点
All the way down the hall!  Keep going!
一直往前走，快点
All the way down! Keep moving.  Come on. Fast as you can!
都蹲下
Okay, get down!
快点
Let's go. Come on.
脸面向墙壁!  保护好你们的头 蹲低身体
Face the wall!  Cover your heads! Stay down!
大家都低下头 都蹲低身体
Heads down, everybody!  Everyone stay down!
都把头低下去!
Get your heads down!
把头低下去.
Get your head down.
待在原地!
Stay against the wall!
不，不! 我的天啊!
No, no! Oh, my God!
特雷!
Trey!
老爸
Dad!
有人受伤吗?
Anybody hurt?
大家都没事.
We're all right.
- 特雷?  - 没事 我很好
- Trey?  - Yeah. I'm good.
你准备好了吗?
You ready?
稍等 先拿一下  拿好了吗?
Oh, hey, can you hold this?  You got it?
- 是我老爸  - 你不接吗?
- My dad.  - Are you gonna answer it?
不 我翘掉了学校的毕业典礼  不接
No. You kidding me? I missed  the whole grad ceremony. No.
他会不会很生气?
Is he gonna be pissed at you?
不会 我相信特雷会拍好的
Nah. You know what?  Trey will have filmed it.
快点 接电话
Oh, come on, pick up.
-特雷 给我你的手机  -好的
- Trey, give me your phone.  - Yeah.
- 特雷?  - 唐尼 你没事吧?
- Trey?  - Donnie, you okay?
爸爸? 是的，我没事
Dad? Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
你在哪?
Where are you?
爸爸 特雷能处理好所有拍摄工作  不会有问题的
Dad, Trey can handle all the filming  and stuff. It's not, like, a problem.
这不重要  你现在安全吗?告诉我你在哪?
Never mind about that. Are you safe?  Tell me where you are.
很安全 我在废弃的造纸工厂
Safe? Yeah. I'm at  the old paper mill.
- 在加纳街?  - 是阿
- On Garner?  - Yeah.
听着,现在情况很紧急
Listen, it's really  important that you...
- 爸爸? 爸爸?  - 唐尼?
- Dad? Dad?  - Donnie?
- 爸爸?  - 在哪里待着别动...
- Dad?  - Stay where you are...
唐尼..
Donnie?
- 唐尼..  - 发生了什么事情?
- Donnie!  - What happened?
手机中断了 摄影机给我
It just cut out. Here.
哇
Whoa.
- 我们应该离开这边  - 是呀
- Maybe we should go.  - Heh. Yeah.
- 是什么声音?  - 我不知道
- What is that?  - I don't know.
- 来吧  - 啊!
- Come on!  - Aah!
好了 没事了
It's all right. It's all right.
- 你要去哪?  - 去找我儿子 他在外面
- Where are you going?  - I gotta get my son. He's out there.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
最新消息...
From our vantage point...
从我们的制高点来看 造成的伤害并没有想像中的大
the damage could have  been a whole lot worse.
龙卷风只是匆匆通过了校区...
The tornado just narrowly  grazed the school...
达里尔 听见了吗?
Daryl, are you hearing this?
...从这段影片可以看出
...as you can see from this footage.
国家气象局目前正在追踪第二起超大暴风...
The National Weather Service is currently  tracking a second supercell...
此刻它正向我们这方向袭来...
moving in our direction.  I know it's hard to imagine...
第二起超大暴风
A second cell.
- 真是越来越危险了  - 怎么会出现另一个暴风?
- This is gonna be bad.  - How can there be another system?
我从来没见过这个  这些上升气流太不可思议了
I've never seen anything like this.  These updrafts are insane.
有倒下的电线杆挡住路了
Got downed power lines.
- 我们被挡住了  - 越是这样彼得越满意
- We're stuck.  - It's all right. I'm about to make his day.
We're gonna send it back
to Don Lemon in the studio.
小心 卢卡斯 电线有电
Heads up, Lucas. Live wire.
有什么新闻?
What else we got?
北边有新状况 正向城镇中心移动.
Activity heading toward  the center of town.
第二起超大暴风?
Second cell?
非常有组织性 钩状回波很大
It's organized.  The hook echo is huge.
我想离它越近越好 可以吗
I wanna set up as close to  the perimeter as possible.
最好是能到正中间
I wanna be in the middle.
- 我可不想再错过了 可以吗  - 我知道了
- I'm not gonna miss it.  - I hear you.
- 雅各布 你那边如何?  - 情况很好
- Jake, how you doing?  - Never better.
情况很好 坚持住 伙计  给你
You hang in there, honey.  That was nothing. Here you go.
传到我的GPS上 我们走吧 出发
Send that to my GPS.  Let's roll. Come on.
你要杯咖啡吗，老大?
You want a coffee with that, boss?
凯特琳?
Kaitlyn?
凯特琳!
Kaitlyn!
- 你受伤了吗?  - 是啊 我的腿
- Are you hurt?  - Yeah. My leg.
腿受伤了!?
Okay. Your leg?
让我看看
Here, let me see it.
痛死我了
It really hurts.
- 啊  - 撑着点
- Ugh.  - Hold on.
好的 没事的 撑着点
Okay. All right, hang on.
- 不要碰它  - 哇
- Don't touch it.  - Ow.
我帮你包扎一下，好吗?
I'm gonna tie this, okay?
- 小心点  - 对不起
- Be careful.  - Sorry.
- 没事吧?  - 没事
- All right?  - Yeah.
特雷 唐尼到那地方去干嘛?
What was Donnie doing  there in the first place?
他跟凯特琳在一起  他早就喜欢她了
He's with Kaitlyn.  He's been in love with her forever.
凯特琳.强森?
Johnston?
是啊 他在帮她拍一个环保的影片资料
Yeah. He's shooting this  video project thing for her.
他为什么不告诉我?
Why didn't he just tell me?
我也不知道 老爸  你不是个好说话的人
I don't know, Dad.  You're so easy to talk to.
我只能这么说
I'm just saying.
哇
Whoa.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
嗨，男孩
Hey, boy.
嗨
Hey.
爸爸 那是切斯特的狗
Dad, that's Chester's dog.
切斯特?
Chester?
切斯特!
Chester!
爸爸 小心点!
Dad, be careful!
你没事吧?
- You okay?  - Had to go looking for shelter.
我正开车前往避难所
Was gonna drive.
让我看看
Let me see.
- 你受伤了吗?  - 打开车门
- You hurt?  - Get the door.
安全带卡住了
The belt's stuck.
我得割断它
I gotta cut him out.
能过来帮帮忙吗?
Hey, can I get some help over here?
给你
Here.
- 我知道不该带着这东西  - 以后再找你算帐
- I know, I'm not supposed to have that.  - We'll talk about that later. Hang on.
- 放在这上面  - 好的
- Put this under him.  - Yep.
- 慢点  - 就这里
- Right there.  - Put him down.
- 你能不能带所有邻居们都去学校?  - 嗯
- Can you get everybody to the high school?  - Uh-huh.
那里有避难所
They've got a storm shelter.
- 你想跟他们一块去吗?  - 不
- You wanna go with them?  - No way.
- 好好照顾他  - 放心吧
- Make sure he's okay.  - You got it.
该死
Oh, shit.
继续
Oh, come on.
再试试你的手机
Try your phone again.
拜托 拜托
Oh, come on, come on, come on.
- 可以了吗?  - 还是没讯号
- Anything?  - There's no signal.
真糟糕
Damn it.
看那些白痴
There are those idiots.
靠边停车
Pull over.
彼得 你们可以先走
Hey, Pete, you can pass us.
- 艾莉森 不能再浪费时间了  - 我知道 我们会赶上的
- Allison, we don't have time to waste.  - Yeah, we'll catch up to you.
大家好 男一号里夫斯驾到
Hello! Your main man Reevis here.
- 我和我的兄弟 唐克  - 性感迷人的唐克
- I'm with my buddy Donk.  - Badonkadonk! Heh.
- 刚才怎么了?  - 我告诉你 仔细听了
- What just happened?  - All right, so check this out.
我刚在龙卷风里了  只有一个字可以形容:
I was in a tornado, right?  And let me tell you. One word:
- "超级爽" 哈哈哈  - 哈哈哈 那是三个字 白痴
- "It sucked." Ha-ha-ha.  - Ha-ha-ha. That's two words, jackass.
我知道是三个字  我是在龙卷风里转晕了
I know. Two words, but I was, like,  getting sucked up in the thing.
幸好刚才你身上带了把刀
It was smart back  there with the knife.
谢谢，我还以为你会骂我呢
Thanks. I thought you'd be mad.
我是很想骂你 把刀给我
Oh, I am. Hand it over.
我们应该在这条路上左转
We should turn left on Main.
不行 我要走高速公路
I'm gonna take the highway.
爸爸，我们可以抄近路沿着玫瑰木大街一直走
Dad, if we out through Main,  we can take Rosewood all the way.
能省20分钟
We save like 20 minutes.
好吧
All right.
- 哈哈哈  - 小伙子们
- Ha-ha-ha.  - Hey, guys!
来吧 干杯
Gentlemen!
你的脑袋在上面太可笑了
It's gonna be damn head. Ha-ha-ha.
- 哈哈哈  - 嘿
- Ha-ha-ha.  - Hey.
- 你们两个得呆在屋里 别在外面  - 哇
- You two need to go inside and stay there.  - Whoa.
你们这帮人干这么烂的事真能拿到钱?
You guys actually get  paid to do this shit?
不像我的工作全是白费了
I'm in the wrong damn job, man.
- 你根本没什么工作  - 嘿
- You don't have a job.  - Heh.
快走吧 艾莉森
Let's go, Allison!
来罐啤酒吧  现在这景象简直是电影僵尸启示录
Grab a brew. It's like a  zombie apocalypse out here.
- 别跟他们浪费时间  - 不 应该这样看着他们
- We're wasting time.  - I don't think we can leave them.
- 听着 我们没责任管神经病  - 他们是喝多了
- Look. They're not our responsibility.  - They're drunk.
- 大伙们  - 哇，哇，哇 你拍到了吗?
- Guys.  - Whoa, whoa, whoa. You getting this?
- 看阿 唐克  - 真棒 快看阿
- Look, look. Donk, Donk.  - Oh. Hell, yeah! Ha, ha!
Hell, yeah.
看那边
Look at it.
- 糟糕 它要去哪?  - 在哪里?
- Whoa, shit! Where did it go?  - Where'd it go? What?
在哪里?...?
Where is it...?
- 快看 它在移动  - 哇
- It's moving, it's moving, it's moving.  - Whoa.
艾莉森 这是怎么回事?
Hey, Allison, what's happening?
继续拍
Keep filming.
- 哇  - 大伙们 看阿
- Whoa!  - Guys! Look at that!
里夫斯 我的天啊
Reevis! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- 是阿!  - 你看见了吗?
- Yeah!  - You getting it?
要命  不
No! No! Holy shit!
- 妈的 我的卡车  - 我的天啊
- My truck!  - Oh, my God!
爸爸
Dad!
快下车到银行里
Get out and run for the bank!
快进去 快
Go! Go! Hurry! Hurry!
该死
Oh, shit!
- 我的天啊  - 爸爸 快点阿
- Oh, my God!  - Dad! Hurry!
你先进去
Go inside!
特雷
Trey!
天啊
God!
撑住
Hang on!
- 我的天啊! 不, 不, 不!  - 撑住!
- Oh, my God! No, no, no!  - Hang on!
爸爸 撑住!
Dad, hold on!
- 天啊  - 我抓住你了
- Oh, God! Aah!  - I've got you!
撑住!
Hold on!
我不会放手的
I won't let you go!
抓紧门边
Grab the door!
不 爸爸
No. Dad, no!
我的天啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
- 艾莉森 你没事吧?  - 来吧 特雷 我们上车
- Allison, you okay?  - Come on, Trey. Let's get in the car.
- 大家都在吗  - 是的
- Everyone here?  - Yeah.
这真是太疯狂了
This is crazy, guys.
糟糕
Oh, shit.
哇
Whoa.
我能用你的手机吗?  我儿子很危险 我的手机没讯号
Hey, can I use your cell?  My son's out there. I got no signal.
可以
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Uh...
我的也没讯号
I don't either.
他在哪?
Where is he?
他之前说在加纳街上的造纸厂
He said he was at an industrial  park on Garner Road.
是从这边往北吗?
Is that north of here?
- 这太吓人了  - 我付钱就是让你拍这个的
- This is crazy.  - This is what we're paying you for.
请等我一下
Give me one second.
你们是怎么了?
Guys, what's going on?
达里尔 真不可思议?  你的朋友居然不想干了
Daryl, can you believe this?  Your buddy here wants to quit.
没说不想干了  给我们一点时间，彼得
Hey. No one's quitting here.  Just give us a minute, Pete.
给你一分钟
You got a minute.
你会没事的 对吗?
You'll be okay. Right?
这太疯狂了 老兄  你看 一辆卡车差点砸在我身上
This is crazy, man, all right?  I mean, a truck almost fell on us.
冷静点 兄弟
Relax.
只要今天熬过去到了下周...
Make it through today,  and by next week...
你口袋会装满了钱  到时你会躺在沙滩上喝着玛格丽塔酒...
you got cash and you are sitting  on a beach sipping margaritas...
搂着你漂亮的女朋友 明白吗?
with that beautiful girlfriend  of yours. All right?
- 我不喜欢喝玛格丽塔酒  - 要相信我
- I don't even like margaritas.  - Heh. Trust me.
走吧 别再浪费时间了  达里尔 把他那该死的摄影机拿过来
Come on, we're wasting time.  Daryl, just take his damn camera from him.
他能搞定的
He's got this.
- 我们为下个暴风准备吧  - 好的
- Let's get ready for the next system.  - All right.
下个暴风?
Another system?
等一下，那是往北走 对吗?
Wait a minute.  That was going north, right?
那是造纸厂的方向
That's toward the paper mill.
能带上我一起过去吗?  我的车已经坏了
I gotta get there. Can you  take us? My car is totaled.
- 抱歉 没时间  - 他的儿子在那边
- Sorry. No time.  - His son's out there.
彼得
Pete.
到了那边别碍手碍脚的
Just stay out of the way.
你们跟我坐厢型车过去吧
You guys can come in the van with me.
- 拿摄影机的孩子跟我一起  - 可以吗? 太好了
- I can take the kid with the camera.  - Really? Sweet.
不行 特雷 你必须跟着我
No, no, Trey, you're staying with me.
你瞧下，Titus才最安全
Look, the Titus is the  safest place for him.
没错 那就是台坦克  我们随后就到
He's right. It's a tank.  We'll be right behind him.
- 到加纳街下车 知道吗?  - 知道
- Just as far as Garner, okay?  - Right.
听着 孩子摄影机要一直开着  结束后 我三千元买你的影片
Keep that camera rolling. When this is  over, I'll give you 3 grand for your tape.
- 三千元?!  - 是的
- Three grand?  - Yeah.
- 没问题  - 一言为定
- Heh. You got it.  - Now we're talking.
我们出发吧
Let's move!
你的腿怎么样了?
How's your leg?
好像好点了
It's a bit better.
来
Here.
- 嗯  - 还好吗?
- Ah.  - All right?
还好
Okay.
从哪学来的?
Where'd you learn that?
我妈曾经是个护士...
Uh, my mom was a nurse...
在我们小时候  她不跟我们说故事却给我们上急救课
so when we were kids, instead of story  time, we'd have, like, CPR lessons.
那时候我特别喜欢看“戴帽子的猫”  不过现在...
At the time I was kind of lobbying  for Cat in the Hat, but now...
好吧，谢谢你了，老妈
Ha, ha. Yeah, thanks, Mom.
- 可以吗?  - 挺好的
- Okay?  - Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
我骗我爸妈说 我是去图书馆
I told my parents I was  going to the library.
你爸爸会来救我们吧?
Your dad is coming, right?
会有人找到我们的
Someone will find us.
你还好吧?
You okay?
知道吗 我一辈子等的就是这样的暴风
Look, I waited my whole  life for a storm like this.
千万别让我失望了
Please don't let me down.
你在联络谁?
Who you trying to reach?
我的女儿格蕾丝
My little girl, Gracie.
我从没离开过她那么长的时间
I've never been away from  her this long before.
她在哪?
Where is she?
跟我父母在一起 离这里有两百英里的地方
She's with my parents about  200 miles to the south.
他们会保护她的
They'll make sure she's safe.
是啊 只是这个时候离开她觉得心神不宁
Yeah. It just really feels wrong to be  away from her right now. You know?
格蕾丝多大了?
How old is Gracie?
快五岁了
She just turned 5.
哇
Wow.
- 正是最麻烦的年龄  - 她是个懂事的孩子
- They're a real handful at that age.  - She's a really good kid.
你另一个儿子多大了?
How old is your other son?
唐尼 17岁
Donnie? He's 17.
这个年纪的孩子不会有事的
He'll be all right. He knows  everything at that age.
自从他母亲去世之后  我总感觉和他有些距离
After his mom died,  I kind of lost him for a while.
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
这就是你们的工作吗?  到处追着麻烦跑?
So is this what you guys do for a living?  Go around chasing trouble?
他们追 我搞研究
They chase. I study.
让我成长许多 没错吧? 达里尔
Makes me the grown-up. Right, Daryl?
还没听说过一次有这么多个
I've never heard of this  many tornadoes before.
这次真的很诡异  两个龙卷风在同一条路径上
It's a freak occurrence. Two storm  fronts taking the same path.
也没什么怪异的  卡特里娜还有乔普林都是这样
It's not freak anymore.  Not after Katrina. Not after Joplin.
一辈子只会看到一次超强暴风  现在居然变成一年一次了
What used to be once-in-a-lifetime seems  to be happening about once a year.
想想桑迪龙卷风的后果吧
Look what happened  with Hurricane Sandy.
无论怎么样，我们都要搞清楚...
Whatever it is, we have  to figure it out...
不然它们会袭击更多以前没出现过的地方
before they start shifting to  places they've never been before.
- 哪些地方?  - 或许是洛杉矶、芝加哥
- Like where?  - Like Los Angeles. Or Chicago.
甚至伦敦
Even London.
有树挡住道路了
Tree blocking the road.
- 我们遇到麻烦了  - 能绕过去吗?
- We got a problem.  - Can you get around that?
没办法
No.
爸爸 这是穆尔帕克公路吧?
Moorpark. Right, Dad?
往西差不多三英里  那里的路可能畅通无阻
It's about three miles west.  It might be clear that far out.
好主意
Good call.
调头往穆尔帕克公路
Doubling back to Moorpark.
你儿子可真棒
That's a great boy you've got.
还记得你妈妈跟你说的最后一句话是什么?
Do you ever think about the last  thing you said to your mom?
每天都在想着
I think about it every day.
呃...
Um...
当时我很生她的气
Because I was pissed at her.
我总能找到生气的理由
I was always pissed  at her for something.
比如说和爸爸离婚 离开我和特雷
For leaving Dad.  For leaving me and Trey.
周末的时候我们经常和她在一起  有次她送我们回来...
We used to spend the weekends  with her, so she was...
她想亲我跟我道别 我只是...
She was dropping us back, and she tried  to kiss me goodbye, and I just...
我几乎没看她一眼 她只好走了
I barely looked at her,  and she walked away.
差不多就这些 这就是最后一次
Yeah, that was it.  That was the last time.
发生什么事?
What happened?
发生车祸
It was a car accident.
- 真抱歉.  - 没关系的
- I'm sorry.  - No.
只是...
It's...
听见了吗?
You hear that?
有人吗?
Hello?
嘿! 嘿! 我们在下面
Hey! Hey, we're down here!
- 有人吗?  - 帮帮我们
- Hello?  - Please help us!
- 发生了什么事?  - 是管线破裂了吧
- What happened?  - I think a pipe burst!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
快点 唐克  你看见什么了?
Get on it, Donk.  You see anything yet?
- 我觉得那台Titus就在前面
- Titus?  - I think the twister cloud's up ahead.  - Twister cloud?
该死 慢点 唐克!  我的屁股要裂了
Shit! Slow down, Donk!  You're busting my balls!
- 直接翻过这座山 会找到他们的  - 不 那不是座山
- Straight over this hill! You'll be fine!  - No! Not the hill!
傻逼
Hey! Moron!
我的天啊 你个傻逼
Oh, my God!
你这白痴
Ugh! Damn! You dumb-ass!
你妹啊
- What the hell, man?  - Whoo! Yeah!
- 没事吧，老兄?  - 当然
- You all right, man?  - Yes! Ha-ha-ha.
哇
Whoa.
没事吧 老兄
Aw. This thing's awesome.
- 这东西太酷了  - 相当狂野
- She's a beast.  - Absolutely.
哇, 这是太酷了.
Wow, this is so cool.
你没事了吧?
You gonna be all right?
其实我不该老对着你发火 知道吗
Look, I know I yell at  you a lot. But listen.
刚开始的时候我也经常吓得不轻
When I first started,  I was scared shitless too.
现在我们寄予厚望的时刻终于来到了...
We got a lot riding on this.  But when the moment comes...
相信我 你一定会安然无恙的
trust me, you're gonna be fine.
是的，老大
Yes, sir.
在雷达上看到它了吗?
You getting this on radar?
是 我看见了  朝着这方向快速过来了
I see it. It's headed  fast in this direction.
我收到三个钩状小回波 也可能是四个
I got three small hook echoes.  Maybe four.
- 你现在能看到它的样子了吗  - 不行 看不到
- D, you getting any visual on this?  - No. Nothing.
我也什么都看没见
I'm not seeing anything, you guys.
上面看的情况怎么样 小子?
What's happening up top, kid?
这也什么都没有 只看到云  等一下，在左边
I got nothing up here. Just clouds.  Wait, there it is. Right there on the left!
- 你们看见了吗?  - 看到了 正在拍呢
- Are you seeing this?  - Yeah, yeah, I got it.
东北方向那边有动静
We got movement to the northeast.
快看看那边
Take a look at that!
伙伴们 它正在分裂
Guys, it's splitting.
- 会形成另一个漏斗云  - 我们后面也有情况
- We're gonna have another funnel.  - Something's happening behind us.
那边也有一个
There's another one.
我们右边有一个
There's one to our right!
两个
Two.
现在变三个了，四个!  天啊 到处都是
There are three. Four!  Shit, they're everywhere!
我们四周有好几个龙卷风正在着陆
We have multiple  vortices touching down.
彼得 这些龙卷风不太稳定  我们得赶紧离开这边
These systems are too erratic.  We gotta get out of here.
天啊 不~
No, no, no!
- 看那东西  - 啊
- Look at that thing!  - Aah!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
我的天啊!
Oh, God!
看那家伙真强啊 老兄
Look at the size of that thing!
我们这辈子都会是影片分享网站上的大明星
We're gonna be YouTube stars  for the rest of our lives!
这比泡妞还爽 唐克
Ha, ha! Better than sex,  Donk! Ha-ha-ha.
你泡过妞吗?
How would you know?
爸爸
Dad!
龙卷风在我们后面
Behind us!
大家都没事吧?
Is everybody all right?
- 没事  - 我没事.
- Yeah.  - I'm okay.
糟糕
Oh, shit.
- 继续拍  - 正拍着呢
- Keep filming!  - Yeah, I got it!
这太不可思议了
This is unbelievable!
- 爸爸!  - 你没事吧?
- Dad!  - Are you all right?
我车门打不开 得从后门出来
I can't get out the side.  We're gonna go through the back.
- 特雷 你没事吧?  - 没事的 我很好
- Trey, you okay?  - Yeah, I'm fine.
快走 快点
Let's go!
- 快点 快点  - 快走 快走
- Come on, come on, come on!  - Come on. Come on.
- 特雷!  - 我在这里!
- Trey!  - Over here!
我们得找掩护大家都上Titus!  快点 来吧
We gotta take cover! Everybody in  the Titus! Run! Let's move! Move!
- 快点  - 快跑
- Come on!  - Let's go!
当心
!  Look out!
快跑
Come on!
大家都到教堂
Everybody head for the church!
- 快走 特雷,跟着我  - 小心
- Come on, Trey, stay with me!  - Look out!
真要命
Holy shit!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
这太厉害了 我必须拍下来
This is amazing! I gotta get this!
雅各布 别拍了
Jake, forget it!
雅各布 快跑
Jake, come on!
艾莉森
Allison!
- 雅各布  - 雅各布
- Jake!  - Jacob!
- 我的摄影机  - 别管摄影机了
- My camera!  - Leave it!
但是里面有我的影片
But I gotta get the footage!
雅各布 快点快走
Jake, come on! Let's go!
糟糕
Shit!
- 不! 不, 不, 不!  - 快跑!
- No! No, no, no!  - Come on!
救命! 不 不 不!
Help me! No, no, no!
- 不 雅各布  - 不 他卷进去了! 艾莉森 他被卷进去了
- No! Jacob!  - No! He's gone! Allison, he's gone!
- 快进来 关上门  - 把门关上
- Get inside!  - Shut the door!
快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on!
蹲下
Get down!
好的
Okay.
糟糕
Oh, shit.
特雷 特雷
Trey. Trey!
我在这里 爸爸
I'm here, Dad.
- 我们得离开这里  - 是呀
- Let's get out of here.  - Yeah.
- 你们要去哪?  - 去找我儿子
- Where are you going?  - I'm getting my son.
再等等 现在外面很危险
Please, wait. It isn't  safe out there.
要是你女儿有危险呢?
What if it was your daughter?
呃...
Um...
如果我们能驾驶箱型车会比走路安全  这你应该明白?
If we can get the van back on the road, we'll  be safer than we would be on foot. Okay?
彼得 你能不能...
Pete, can you hook up...?
你只在乎这些东西吗?
Is that all you care about?
不
No. No.
彼得，雅各布死了
Jacob's dead, Pete.
如果不是因为你 他应该还活着
He'd probably still be alive  if it wasn't for you.
你觉得雅各布的死是我的错?
You think what happened is my fault?
他之所以在外面不是他自己愿意的 对吧?
I mean, he wasn't out there  shooting for himself, was he?
他是为了你 拍你的纪录片...
He was getting your  shot for your movie...
因为你告诉他没有什么比龙卷风重要  而且你还不让他离开
because you told him nothing else  matters, and you wouldn't let him go.
不
No.
不能怪彼得
It wasn't Pete.
该怪我
It was me.
我带他到这里的 是我的错
I brought him here. It was my fault.
别这样 这些都不该发生的
No. No. None of this  should have happened.
你一定要帮他找到儿子
You gotta help him find his son.
我会的 那你呢?
I will. What about you?
我会待在这里
I'm gonna stay here.
看看能不能找到雅各布的父母  跟他们联系上
I'll see if I can find Jacob's parents.  Get in contact with them.
好吧
Okay.
- 帮忙堵住缝隙  - 什么?
- Help me close up the gap!  - Huh?
帮忙把水堵住
Help me close it up!
- 这样能堵住水吗?  - 试试看
- Can you stop it coming in?  - I'm trying!
卢卡斯 你要来吗?
Lucas, you coming?
彼得...
Pete...
你自己决定吧，反正我得继续
Suit yourself. I gotta finish this.
特雷 快上车
Trey, come on. Get in.
- 我们去找你哥哥  - 好的
- Let's go find your brother.  - All right.
加油 宝贝
Come on, baby.
加油
Come on.
真是个好孩子
That's my girl.
爸爸 外面天气越来越糟了
Dad, it's getting worse out there.
还是没有讯号
Still no signal.
我的手机 完全不能用了
My phone. It's not working.
试试看你的手机
Try yours.
我的也没讯号
No, there's no signal.
- 到那个洞口试试看  - 好的
- Try it through the gap right there.  - Okay.
你的手臂刚好碰的到洞口
Your arm can fit.
- 我的天啊 有一格讯号  - 开扩音
- Oh, my God. There's a bar, there's a bar.  - Put it on speakerphone!
我是盖瑞 请留言
This is Gary. Leave a message.
爸爸 爸爸快来救我们
Dad! Dad! Please help us!
我们这边的房子坍塌了  现在水不断地灌进来...
The building fell down on top of us,  and there's water pouring in...
我不知道还有多少时间
and I don't know how long we've got!
爸爸!
Dad!
不~
Aah.
该死
Oh, shit!
Oh, shit.
对不起 没电了
I'm sorry. It's dead.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你们还好吧?  我正带着些人前往避难所
Are you folks all right? I'm taking  these people to the shelter.
- 你有去过造纸厂了吗?  - 去过了 那边整个地方都毁了
- You been by the industrial park?  - Sure have. Whole place has been flattened.
- 有没有看到一位17岁的男孩和一位女孩  - 抱歉 我没看到任何人
- Did you see anyone? A boy? A girl?  - I didn't see anybody. I'm sorry.
- 可能他已经回到学校了  - 万一没有呢? 还是得去看看
- Maybe he made it to the school.  - What if he didn't? We gotta go.
跟你们说 我刚从广播上听到  所有警报器都坏了
Listen. I heard on the radio,  all the warning sirens are down.
如果真有龙卷风来 你们是不会知道的
If a tornado's coming,  you're not gonna know it.
可以了
Okay.
妈妈
Mom.
爸爸
Dad.
我想对你们说声谢谢
I just wanna thank  you for everything.
今天早上我下楼时是打算跟你们打招呼的...
I was gonna come down the stairs  this morning to say goodbye...
但是我下楼的时候你们都出去了
but when I came you  were already gone.
我收到了一通留言
I got a message.
爸爸 爸爸快来救我们
Dad! Dad! Please help us!
我们这边的房子坍塌了，现在水不断地灌进来...
The building fell down on top of us,  and there's water pouring in...
- ...我不知道还有多少时间  - 我的天啊
- ...and I don't know how long we've got!  - Oh, my God.
我想告诉你们 我不孤单
You should know I'm not alone.
唐尼在这里
Donnie's here.
他对我非常好
He's been really sweet.
所以还算不错
So it's kind of okay.
我非常爱你们
I love you so much.
你知道吗
Guess what.
我上周一直忙着时光胶囊的事  忙着拍别人的未来...
I spent the last week filming time  capsules about people's futures...
却把自己的给忘了
and now it looks like  I don't have one.
所以...
So, uh...
如果没有未来了 那就...
if there's no future...
聊聊过去吧
we should talk about the past.
呃...
Um...
从小到大有不少的倒霉事
Some bad shit happened along the way.
不过 每个人都倒霉过
You know, like it does  to everybody, I guess.
是我...
And...
是我没有向前看 我还总是怪罪老爸
And I didn't move on, Dad.  I blamed you.
老是找他麻烦 我非常后悔
I really gave you shit,  and I wish I hadn't.
真的 真的非常后悔
I so wish I hadn't.
现在后悔还来的及吗?
No point in wishing now, huh?
我到底想说什么? 嗯...
What do I wanna say? Um...
别怪特雷
Go easy on Trey.
他肯定会说这一切都是他的错
He's gonna tell you that  this is all his fault.
这是他的主意 其实不是
This was his idea. But it wasn't.
特雷就是这样 总是爱耍帅
It's just Trey.  His attention-seeking behavior.
是我的主意
My idea.
我的错
My fault.
特雷 你就应该坚持做你自己  老弟 你真的很棒
Trey, you should be the person you always  were, dude, because you're awesome.
你是最棒的 我以你为荣...
You're awesome and  I'm proud of you...
珍惜每一天 把每天当成最后的日子
and just live every  day like it's your last.
因为世事难料
Because, shit, someday it will be.
我第一次知道自己要说什么
And for once, I know  what I'm talking about.
爸爸...
And, Dad...
老爸，我爱你
Dad, I love you.
我真的爱你 可是对不起
I really love you and I'm sorry.
真的非常抱歉
Okay, I'm sorry.
好了
Okay. Sorry.
抱歉
Sorry.
过来
Come here.
好了
Okay.
没事了
All right.
快点
Come on.
在这里左转
Take a left here.
唐尼
Donnie!
特雷
Trey!
去看看那边
Look!
有人吗?
Hello?
这是唐尼的
It's Donnie's!
唐尼
Donnie!
你在哪?
Where are you?
凯特琳!
Kaitlyn!
到这边来
Over here!
他之前说有说有水灌进来 对吧?
He said there was  water pouring in, right?
爸爸 我在这里!
Dad! Over here!
听好，大家都别动
Listen! Nobody move!
我们在这里 在这里!
We're over here!
- 唐尼!  - 爸爸
- Donnie!  - Dad!
- 他在哪?  - 别怕
- Where is he?  - It's okay.
- 唐尼 我来了  - 找到你了
- Donnie, I'm here!  - We got you.
别怕 我来了  我是爸爸 你听见我声音了吗?
It's okay! I'm here! I got you!  It's Dad! Can you hear me?
爸爸! 特雷!
Dad! Trey!
爸爸，能看见吗
Dad!
爸爸 赶紧救他上来
Dad, you've gotta help him!
你能游过去吗? 这里有个大洞
Can you swim through?  There's a gap here!
你撑住
Now you hold on!
唐尼
Donnie!
盖瑞 这东西太重了
Gary, I can't move it!
必须把它搬开，把这柱子推开  来啊 用力推
We gotta move this! We gotta move  this I-beam! Come on, push it!
- 不行 推不动  - 爸爸
- It's not gonna move.  - Dad!
- 唐尼 没事的  - 最好把这个拉出来
- Donnie, you're okay.  - Help me get her out.
你做的很好
You're doing good.
我们会救你出来
We're gonna get you out.
特雷 你在做什么?
Trey, what are you doing?
小心
Watch out!
你现在稍微离开点
Okay, I need you to duck down!
我们要把这柱子搬开  明白吗 唐尼?
We're gonna move this beam!  You understand?
Got it!
你们都没事吧?
You guys Okay?
好了
I got it. I got it. All right.
- 凯特琳，把手给我  - 你没事吧?
- Kaitlyn, come on.  - Are you okay?
- 抓住你了 抓紧  - 用力，拉她上来
- I got you, I got you.  - Let's go, let's go. Get her out.
唐尼
Donnie!
- 唐尼  - 我抓住他了
- Donnie!  - I got him.
把他拉上来
Pull him up!
I got his head.
上来了
Get him up.
唐尼?
Donnie?
太好了
Right here. Here we go.
唐尼!
Donnie!
唐尼?
Donnie?
把这个垫在他的头下面
Put this under his head.
他没呼吸了
He's not breathing!
天啊
Oh, God!
- 唐尼!  - 我的天啊
- Donnie!  - Oh, my God.
唐尼!
Donnie!
呼吸!
Breathe!
加油啊
Come on!
天啊 把水咳出来
Go on. Cough it up.  There you go. Come here.
儿子继续把水咳出来
There you go, son. Cough it up.
你活过来了
Here. It's okay.
没事了
I got you.
- 凯特琳  - 她没事 就在旁边而已
- Kaitlyn.  - It's okay. She's here.
没事了
It's okay.
我爱你 儿子
I love you, son.
把他救过来了
We got him now. We got him now.
过来
Come here.
- 我爱你们两个  - 唐尼.
- I love you both.  - Donnie.
我爱你们
So much.
看来你们需要帮忙
I thought you might need some help.
真没想到我居然会高兴再看见你
Never thought I'd be happy  to see your face again.
来拿走我的硬盘
Getting my hard drives.
- 你一直在这里吗?  - 是啊
- You were down there?  - Yeah.
-摄影机一直在拍摄?  -恩
- Camera rolling?  - Uh-huh.
- 恩  - 这才是我认识的彼得
- Mm.  - Yeah, there's the guy I know.
- 大伙 我们必须离开这里  - 快点
- Guys, we gotta get out of here.  - Come on.
来吧 大家都上Titus
Everybody in the Titus.
我们正在追踪一场巨大的龙卷风
We are tracking a massive tornado.
彼得 看见这个了吗?
Pete, you seeing this?
- 第二个龙卷风态势已经形成了  - 是的 我看见了
- There's a second tornado formation.  - I see it.
这个龙卷风现在正往西北部移动  现在 这个龙卷风刚刚着陆
This storm is heading northwest.  There. And it just touched down.
有两个巨大的龙卷风正向西威尔顿镇中西移动
We now have two very large tornadoes  moving towards the town of Silverton.
绍尔县的居民必须立刻前往最近的避难所
All residents of Shaw County  should seek shelter immediately.
两个龙卷风正在合并 风速可能会到达...
They are converging, which could  generate wind speeds of up to a...
天啊 它们开始合并了
There! There they go!  They just converged.
现在龙卷风的风速已经超过了每小时三百英里
We are looking at wind speeds inside  the funnel of over 300 miles per hour.
这绝对是5级的龙卷风
This is definitely an EF5.
这是我这辈子见过最大的龙卷风
This is the biggest  tornado I've ever seen.
- 那是学校  - 全城都危险了
- The school.  - The whole town's in there.
警报系统已经坏掉了
Warning systems are out.
所有的人都...
They're sitting ducks.
听着 所有人都马上离开这里
Okay, everybody out. Now. Let's go.
快出去! 快 快走
Hurry! Get out! Go!
你在干嘛?  你是不是疯了?
What are you doing?  You out of your mind?
- 有另一个龙卷风正往这里移动  - 所以这时候你让我们出去?
- There is another tornado heading this way.  - And you want us to go outside?
- 你根本就不明白  - 没错 必须离开这里
- You don't understand.  - You have to.
我的天 这里是避难所啊
This is the storm shelter,  for chrissake.
- 这次没用了  - 能不能请你相信我们?
- Not for this.  - Would you believe us?
我们已经看到它的破坏力了
We've been out there.  We know what this can do.
我不会冒这个险  这里有上百个避难的学生
I am not going to risk it.  I've got hundreds of people here.
继续待在这里的话 这些学生就要遇难了
You will have hundreds of  dead people if you stay.
先生，我一辈子都在研究暴风 了解吗?
Sir. I've studied storms  all my life, all right?
这次比以往任何一次的情况都严重  你能明白我的意思吗?
This is bigger than any storm that  has ever been. Can you hear that?
- 几秒钟就能把这里夷为平地  - 她说的没错
- It will flatten this building in seconds.  - Exactly.
不管你同不同意  我们都要让所有人上搭那几辆巴士
With or without you, we're getting  these people onto those buses.
- 特雷和我在一起 千万别走散了  - 好的
- Trey, stay with me. Stay close.  - Okay.
大家赶快上车 快点
Come on, everybody!  Get on the buses! Move!
我们得走了
We gotta go.
快走 那一辆
That one! That one over there!
快点 快
- Stay with us!  - Let's go! Let's go!
那边那辆 快走
Come on, move!
特雷 给我把摄影机放下 赶快上车
Trey, put the camera  down and get on the bus.
- 我来了  - 好的 快点
- I'm coming.  - Okay. Go, go, go.
同学们 快
Come on, folks.
快点 要出发了
Come on! Let's go!
快上来 要走了
Everybody on. Move, move, move.
大家都上车 快点
Come on, get in there.
快上来 特雷快上车
Trey, get in.
- 上来 特雷 快上来  - 来了
- Come on, Trey, come on, come on.  - I'm coming, I'm coming.
坐稳了
Hold on.
糟糕，卢卡斯 你在拍吗?
Holy shit. Lucas, you getting this?
是啊 正拍着呢
Yeah. We good.
- 我们安全吗?  - 龙卷风的速度还在加快
- How we looking?  - It's still picking up speed.
爸爸 高压电塔要倒了
Dad! Dad, the tower's coming down!
- 哇 哇 哇! 小心!  - 坐稳了
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! Look out!  - Hang on!
爸爸 小心
Dad, be careful!
- 过不去了 没有路可以绕过去  - 我们没时间了
- We can't get through. There's no way around.  - We don't have any time.
- 我们得回头  - 好吧
- We gotta go back.  - Okay.
- 嘿! 你没事吧?  - 没事
- Hey, are you okay?  - Yeah.
快跟我们走
Come in the bus.  Come in the bus with us.
我们得倒车得回去找其他的路
You guys, we gotta back up!  We gotta go back and find a road!
盖瑞 我们得找个避风处 不能待在空地
Gary, we need cover.  We can't stay in the open.
风速太快了 我们跑不过龙卷风
It's moving too fast.  We're not gonna outrun it.
路被堵死了 我们得调头
The road's blocked.  We gotta turn around.
- 爸爸 把车停路边  - 什么?
- No, Dad, pull over up here.  - What?
爸爸 相信我好吗? 我在这边拍过影片  那边有个下水道
Dad, trust me, okay? I filmed here.  There's a storm drain. Right over there.
- 好 大家都下车  - 好了 下车 快点下车
- Okay, everybody get off.  - All right, come on! Come on!
大家往这边走
All right, this way!
Come on, you guys.  Let's go. Let's go.
- 快点  - 大家都跟上 快点
- Come on!  - Follow me this way!
爸爸 这边封死了 我们进不去
Dad! Dad! We can't get in this way!
- 从维修孔进去  - 维修孔?
- Go in through the manhole!  - Manhole?
- 你有铁棍吗?  - 有
- You got a crowbar?  - Yeah.
- 我还没见过这样的工地  - 卢卡斯
- I've never seen anything like this.  - Lucas!
用力
Come on.
一起用力
Here we go.
- 好了 大家都进去  - 大家都进去
- Okay, everybody in.  - Everybody in!
- 快点 快进去 快  - 下一个 唐尼
- Come on. Let's go. Go! Go!  - Okay. Okay. Donnie!
快进去
Get in.
天啊
Jesus!
快 快
Come on! Come on! Hurry!
快下去
Come on!
- 快啊 快下去  - 快点
- Now! Hurry up!  - Come on, come on!
卢卡斯 快下去
Lucas, get in! Go, move! Go!
- 你们都快下来  - 好的
- Right behind me, guys!  - Yeah, go!
- 你们都没事吧?  - 没事的
- You guys okay?  - Yeah.
- 来帮帮忙  - 来了
- Give me a hand.  - I got it.
- 关上它  - 关上它
- Close it!  - Come on!
加油
Oh, shit!
- 大家都没事吧?  - 卡车把另一边砸开了! 撑住!
- You guys all right?  - The truck opened the other end! Hang on!
这里会变成风道 大家要紧紧抓牢
It's gonna be a wind tunnel  in here! Hold on tight!
- 我的天啊 栅栏松开了  - 抓紧了
- Oh, my God, the grate's loose!  - Hold on!
- 我们要被吹出去了  - 低下你的头
- We're gonna get sucked out!  - Keep your head down!
这段影片跟数据有一天会救很多人的
Hey, this footage and data  could save lives one day!
你要干什么?
What are you doing?
彼得?
Pete?
- 不 等等  - 艾莉森
- No, no! Wait!  - Allison!
彼得
Pete!
卢卡斯 给我对讲机
Lucas! Give me that!
彼得 求求你 快回来
Peter, please, come back!
盖瑞
Gary!
不 艾莉森 我抓不到
No! Allison! I can't reach!
- 给我你的手  - 啊!
- Give me your hand!  - Aah!
来吧
Come on!
快来
Come on. Come here!
艾莉森过来
Allison! Here. Come on.
你没事吧?
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
好了 放下抓锚
Okay, anchor down.
- 他在做什么?  - 他要堵住那个孔
- What's he doing?  - He's trying to plug the hole!
糟了 没法固定
Damn it. She won't stay anchored.
艾莉森 艾莉森
Allison! Allison!
能把绞盘钩在坚固的东西上吗?
Can you hitch the winch  to something solid?
- 卡车  - 好的
- The truck!  - Yeah.
- 松开绞盘  - 在这里
- The release.  - Here.
我抓住了
Okay, I got it.
- 好了 钩住了  - 好了 彼得弄好了 已经绑紧了
- We're good!  - All right, Pete, we're set.
You can tighten her up.
好了
Okay, then.
Titus决战龙卷风
Titus versus tornado.
- 爸爸 撑住  - 盖瑞
- Dad, hang on!  - Gary!
撑住!
Hang on!
怎么了? 过去了?
Is that it? Is it over?
彼得 怎么样? 结束了吗?
Pete, what's happening?  Did it pass us?
还没有结束
It's not gonna last.
我们在龙卷风眼里
We're in the eye.
上帝
Oh, God.
大伙听我说 待会风力会更强更大  大家都要小心 都抓紧了
Guys, the trailing winds will be  even stronger! You've gotta hang on!
好的
Okay.
一定要抓紧了
Hold on tight.
抓紧
Hold on!
唐尼 快蹲下
Donnie! Get down!
这里支撑不住了
It's not gonna hold!
彼得
Peter!
不!
No!
抓住我的手! 不!
Grab my hand! No!
- 不!  - 盖瑞!
- No!  - Gary!
我们就在这边静待观察
And let's see.  We're gonna stay right here.
看看它是否还会卷土重来
We're gonna see if it re-cycles.
它逐渐变成桶状的样子
It's becoming more  of a barrel-shaped.
楔形面略为下降了一点
The wedge has decreased a little bit, and it  looks like it's roping out at Air Depot Road.
看起来会在艾尔德普特路消失
Look at the rope on that thing.
大家看看这东西变绳形  上面螺旋云看上去还是很接近地面
Feeder band looks like it's pretty low to  the ground. It's way lower than we are.
它彻底消失了
There it is. It's gone, Mike.
- 大家都没事吧?  - 我没事
- Everybody okay?  - I'm fine.
- 我们都没事  - 你没事
- Yeah, we're good.  - You're okay.
特雷?
Trey?
这个龙卷风路径延伸至少长达十英里远
This was a storm that was on the ground  for at least 10 miles before it hit.
...遭到巨型龙卷风袭击，破坏力极大
...assault by giant tornadoes.  And look how powerful they are.
其中一个龙卷风  已经被列为史上“最强龙卷风”
One tornado is already being called  the largest tornado in history.
这个超强暴风带来一场冰雹...
The intense storm that  set off the twisters...
大小介于高尔夫球跟棒球之间
dropped golf ball to  baseball-sized hail.
虽然无法避免  超强暴风造成许多伤亡
There's no denying the tragedy  that we've all endured here today.
但是你们知道...
But you know...
我们的信念会带着我们度过难关  重建家园
our faith will carry us through,  and we will rebuild.
彼得的事我很难过
I'm sorry about Pete.
嘿，小宝贝
Hey, little bug.
嗨
Hey.
没事，妈妈没事，放心
No, Mama's okay. I'm okay.
我答应你
I am. I promise.
马上就回家
I'm coming home.
是的，妈妈马上回家了
Yeah, Mama's coming home.
我也爱你
I love you too.
25年后?
In 25 years?
我觉得无所谓了
It doesn't matter, you know?
必须珍惜现在的日子
Just taking it one day at a time.
好好度过每一天
Every day's just fine.
因为我还活着
Because I'm alive.
活着就好
That's it.
什么都无所谓了
Nothing else matters.
有时候我觉得人类非常的疯狂
Sometimes I think the human  race as a species is crazy.
但是在危急的情况下...
But when the chips are down...
像我们这样当个普通人...
ordinary people, like you and me...
才是最棒的
are good.
我很喜欢这样
I like that.
虽然我和彼得经常起争执...
You know, Pete and  I had our moments...
但是我知道他每天活着的意义
but I know why he got  up every morning.
也知道他为什么牺牲了自己
And I know why he gave up his life.
他想做点有意义的事情 还有...
He wanted to make a difference and...
呃..
Um...
希望这部影片可以完成他的遗愿
Well, hopefully this film  will help accomplish that.
对吗?
Huh?
呃，其实当时 真不知道能不能活下来
Uh, to be honest,  it didn't look good back there.
但是坚持过来了
But we made it.
因为我们一起相互扶持，而且我们还...
We stuck together, and here we are.
活着
Alive.
我会怀着感激的心情  在25年后 回忆这段经历
I'm just grateful that we'll be able  to look back on this in 25 years.
25年后? 哇 那时候你变得非常老了吧
Twenty-five years? Wow.  You are gonna be so old.
- 嘿  - 说不定头发也掉光了
- Heh.  - And probably bald too.
行了吧，你这段要剪掉
All right, you're cut off.
唐尼，你有什么话想说?
Donnie, you have  something you wanna say?
呃，我不觉得一定要说什么
Uh, I don't think we really have  to say anything, you know?
我们都在一起
We're all here now. Together.
才是最重要的
And that's all that matters.
是的，没错
Yeah, it is.
好了，赶紧去工作吧
Okay. Let's get back to work.
嗨! 唐克!
Hey! Donk!
唐克，你在哪
Donk, where are you?
在这里!
Over here!
嘿，你怎么倒着了?
Hey, you're upside down!
不，是你倒悬着  你还在一棵树上
No, you're upside down!  And you're in a tree!
恩，你也是啊
Well, so are you!
哦，是喔
Oh, yeah.
摄影机还能用吗?
That camera still working?
-可以  -哈哈
- Yeah, it is!  - Ha, ha.
-老兄，我们要发大财了  -呵呵，哈哈
- Man, we are gonna be so rich!  - Ha-ha-ha.
该死!唐克
Oh, shit! Donk!